State University of New York, University Faculty Senate; Collection apap093
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Administrative Files, 1944-1978; 2; 0.67 cubic ft.
  - Board of Trustees, 1960-1976; 2.1
    This is a small group of records relating to actions of the Board of Trustees of the State University of New York and includes organizational charts, rosters of members of the Board, and general statements.
    Arranged Alphabetically
    - General Statements, 1967-1976 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 1)
    - Members' Rosters, 1974-1976 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 2)
    - Organizational Charts, SUNY, 1960-1976 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 3)
    - Organizational Description of Central Staff, SUNY, 1977 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 4)
    - Policies of Board of Trustees, 1966-1970; Undated (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 5)
    - Summary of Action, 1975 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 6)
  - By-laws, 1954-1974; 2.2
    This sub-series contains copies of the University Faculty Senate by-laws.
    Arranged Chronologically
    - By-laws, 1954-1958; 1963-1969 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 7)
    - By-laws and Manual, 1974 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 8)
  - Collective Bargaining Issues, 1968-1970; 2.3
    Material relating to the Taylor Law and collective bargaining issues is included here, as well as documents relating to a lawsuit against the University Faculty Senate, et al.
    - Collective Bargaining Issues, 1968-1970 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 9)
    - Collective Bargaining Issues, Governors Negotiating Committee, 1968-1970 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 10)
    - Collective Bargaining Issues, Survey, University at Albany, 1970 (Box 1 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1972; 2.4
    This sub-series contains correspondence of individual University at Albany Senators interspersed with other material in some cases. The sub-series was assembled from original files labeled miscellaneous, and several folders of mixed correspondence pertaining to the business of the University Faculty Senate.
    - Foster Arnold, 1972-1974 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 1)
    - Morris, Robert, 1968-1971 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 2)
    - Norton, Joseph, 1966-1968 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 3)
    - Norton, Joseph L., 1969-1972 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 4)
    - Office of the President, UFS, 1969-1971 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 5)
    - Tibbetts, Ralph J., 1966-1969 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 6)
    - University Faculty Senate Office, 1953 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 7)
    - University Faculty Senate Office, 1962-1968 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 8)
    - University Faculty Senate Office, 1969 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 9)
    - University Faculty Senate Office, 1970-1974 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 10)
    - Wheeler, Paul, 1968-1970 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Administrative Files, 1944-1977; 2.5
    This sub-series contains U.F.S. press releases. The sub-series also contains information on the dispute regarding the professional status of librarians as well as the lawsuit filed against Frank C. Erk, et al. by the New York City law firm of Kaye, Scholer, Fierman, Hays, and Handler.
    - Contract Colleges and the State University, Background Data, 1944-1949 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 12)
    - Controversy, Recognition of Assistant Librarians, 1968-1969 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 13)
    - Senate Elections, 1967-1973 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 14)
    - Lawsuit, Kaye, Scholer, Fierman, Hays and Handler vs. Frank Erk, et al, 1971-1972 (Box 2 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 15)
    - "Origins and Development, State University of NY", [Possibly by John Spencer], 1977; Draft Copy (Box 3 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 1)
    - Public Statements, 1969-1970; Undated (Box 3 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 2)
    - Responsibilities and Perogatives of Faculty Senators, Draft Statement, Undated (Box 3 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 3)
    - Rosters, University Faculty Senate Members, 1963-1971 (Box 3 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 4)
    - Selection of Chancellor, 1970 (Box 3 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 5)
  - Reports to the University Faculty Senate, 1956-1973; 2.6
    This sub-series contains reports to the University Faculty Senate from President Frank C. Erk and others.
    - Final Report of the Joint Task Force on General Education, 1998 (Box 3 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 6)
    - Final Report, Survey of the Campus Budget Process, 2002 (Box 3 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 7)
    - Report From the President of the University Faculty Senate, Frank C. Erk, 1970 (Box 3 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 8)
    - Report to the Faculty Senate by Chancellor Ernest L. Boyer, Potsdam, NY, 1972 (Box 3 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 9)
    - Report to the Faculty of University at Albany, 1956-1973 (Box 3 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 10)
    - Synopsis, Senate Action and Chancellors Report, 1968-1970 (Box 3 (2-Administrative Files), Folder 11)
- Committees and Councils, 1966-1974; 3; 1.33 cubic ft.
  This is a large series that covers the activities of the committees and associated councils and conferences relating to their work. Includes reports, guidelines, statements, correspondence, and minutes of meetings and retreats. Also included is a sub-series detailing the Committee on Undergraduate Programs.
  Arranged by Committee.
  - Admissions Ad Hoc Committee, 1967 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 1)
  - Advisory Committees 1968-1969, Undated (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 2)
  - Annual Assemblies, University Faculty Senate Committee on Conferences and Assemblies, 1967-1969 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 3)
  - Budget Committee, 1968-1969; Undated (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 4)
  - Chancellors Panel on University Purposes, Preliminary Reports, 1970 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 5)
  - Committee Structure, 1966-1974 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 6)
  - Council on Linguistics, 1973 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 7)
  - Economic Status of the Faculty Committee, 1966-1970 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 8)
  - Executive Committee, 1970-1973 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 9)
  - Executive Committee, Faculty Senate Statement to the Governor's Negotiating Committee on Professional Salaries, 1967 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 10)
  - Executive Committee, Reports on Meetings, 1967-1969 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 11)
  - Executive Committee, Reports on Meetings, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 12)
  - Expanding Educational Opportunity, 1968-1970 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 13)
  - Expanding Educational Opportunity Committee, 1971-1974 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 14)
  - Expanding Educational Opportunity, Evaluation Questionnaire for Educational Opportunity Programs of SUNY, 1971 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 15)
  - Expanding Educational Opportunity, University-Wide Conference, 1969 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 16)
  - Governance Committee, 1968-1971; Undated (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 17)
  - Graduate Program Committee, 1969-1971 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 18)
  - Grievance Committee, 1969-1972 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 19)
  - International Studies and World Affairs Committee, 1967-1973 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 20)
  - International Studies and World Affairs Program, Remarks Given to University Faculty Senate Assembly, 1967 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 21)
  - Library Resources Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 22)
  - Personnel Policies Committee, 1962-1972 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 23)
  - Personnel Policies, Position Paper on Tenure, Draft, 1972 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 24)
  - Procedures, Joint Committee Meeting, 1968 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 25)
  - Professional Rights and Responsibilities Committee, 1967-1971 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 26)
  - Professional Rights and Responsibilities Committee, 1972 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 27)
  - Professional Rights and Responsibilities Committee, 1973 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 28)
  - Professional Rights and Responsibilities Committee, 1974; Undated (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 29)
  - Public Relations Council, 1970-1974 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 30)
  - Research Committee, 1967-1971 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 31)
  - Research Report of the Actions of the Committee on Biology Relative to the Marine Sciences, SUNY, 1968 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 32)
  - Research Report of the Subcommittee on Facilities for Fresh Water and Terrestrial Ecology, SUNY, 1968 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 33)
  - Resolutions, 1969 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 34)
  - Student Affairs, Committee Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 35)
  - University Faculty Programs Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 36)
  - University Faculty Programs, Invitational Conference, 1970 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 37)
  - University Planning Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 38)
  - University Planning Committee, 1969-1971 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 39)
  - Faculty Senate Workshop, Committee on Undergraduate Program, "The Professor, the Student and the Learning Relationship", 1969 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 40)
  - Faculty Senate Workshop, Committee on Undergraduate Program, "The Professor, the Student and the Learning Relationship", 1969 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 41)
  - An American Educator in Paris, By J. Murdoch Dawley, 1969 (Box 1 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 42)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Programs, 1968 (Box 2 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 1)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Programs, 1969 (Box 2 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 2)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Programs, 1970-1971; Undated (Box 2 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 3)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Programs, Chancellor's Admissions Advisory Panel, 1968 (Box 2 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 4)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Programs, Innovative Programs, 1970-1971 (Box 2 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 5)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Programs, Committee Meeting, Albany, 1967-March 1969 (Box 2 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 6)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Programs, Committee Meeting, Albany, 1969 December (Box 2 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 7)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Programs, Committee Meeting, Albany, 1970 February (Box 2 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 8)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Programs, Committee Meeting, Albany, 1970 April (Box 2 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 9)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Programs, Committee Reports, 1968-1971 (Box 2 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 10)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Programs, Committee Retreat, 1968 (Box 2 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 11)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Programs, Committee Retreat, 1969 (Box 2 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 12)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Programs, Committee Retreat Packet, 1969 (Box 2 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 13)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Programs, Committee Retreat, 1970 (Box 2 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 14)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Programs, "Student-Faculty Ratios in the State University of New York", A Proposed Statement, 1969 (Box 2 (3-Committees and Councils), Folder 15)
- Publications, 1949-2002; 4; 1.33 cubic ft.; 1.33 cubic foot
  Included are bound volumes published by the UFS as well as State University of New York publications and miscellaneous background information from other sources.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Directories, 1953-2002; 4.1
    Includes State University of New York directories, Faculty and UFS directories, and directories of local councils and boards of trustees.
    - Directory of Business Management Personnel, State University of New York, 1967 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 1)
    - Local Councils and Boards of Trustees, Additions to Directory, 1965-1966 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 2)
    - Local Councils and Boards of Trustees, Directory State University of New York, 1969 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 3)
    - Personnel Directory, Office of Educational Development, 1971-1972 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 4)
    - State University of New York Directory, 1970 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 5)
    - State University of New York Directory, 1976-1977 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 6)
    - State University of New York Directory, 1977-1978 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 7)
    - State University of New York Directory, 1979 Spring (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 8)
    - State University of New York Directory, 1980-1981 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 9)
    - State University of New York Directory, 1983 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 10)
    - State University of New York Directory, 1984 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 11)
    - State University of New York Directory, Board of Trustees, Campus Presidents, Central Administration, 1980-1981 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 12)
    - State University of New York Directory of the Faculties, 1953-1954 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 13)
    - State University of New York Directory of the Faculties, 1954-1955 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 14)
    - State University of New York Directory of the Faculties, 1955-1956 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 15)
    - State University of New York Directory of the Faculties, 1956-1957 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 16)
    - State University of New York Directory of the Faculties, 1957-1958 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 17)
    - State University of New York Directory of the Faculties, 1960-1961 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 18)
    - State University of New York Faculty Senate Directory, 1969-1970 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 19)
    - State University of New York Faculty Senate Directory, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 20)
    - State University of New York Faculty Senate Directory, ca. 1971-1972 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 21)
    - State University of New York Faculty Senate Directory, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 22)
    - State University of New York Faculty Senate Directory, 1973-1974 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 23)
    - State University of New York Faculty Senate Directory, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 24)
    - State University of New York Faculty Senate Directory, 1981-1982 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 25)
    - State University of New York Faculty Senate Directory, 1997-1998 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 26)
    - State University of New York Faculty Senate Directory, 2001-2002 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 27)
  - Handbooks and Reports, 1949-1996; 4.2
    Contains Instructions to the Senators handbooks, UFS reports, and overviews and assessments published by the UFS.
    - Annual Financial Report, 1996 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 28)
    - Annual Report of Sponsored Research (Division of Research and Graduate Studies), Office for Research, 1991-1993 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 29)
    - "Assessment at SUNY: Principles, Process and Case Studies", 1992 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 30)
    - "Background and Opportunity of the State University of New York", 1949 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 31)
    - Budget Handbook, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 32)
    - Chancellor's Report, SUNY, 1970-1971; 1987-1988 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 33)
    - Facts Book, SUNY, 1976 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 34)
    - Facts Book, SUNY, 1981 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 35)
    - Facts Book, SUNY, 1982 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 36)
    - Financial and Statistical Data, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 37)
    - "Five Key Decisions", Clifton R. Wharton Jr., Chancellor SUNY, Ca. 1979 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 38)
    - Handbook for Faculty and Staff, 1968 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 39)
    - Income Fund Reimbursable Program, Overview, 1998 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 40)
    - Instructions to Senators and Committee Members, 1967-1970 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 41)
    - Report of Committee on Personnel Policies, 1953 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 42)
    - Report of State-Operated Campuses and Statutory Colleges Sources of Revenue/Survey of Fees, Volume 1, 1992 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 43)
    - Report of State-Operated Campuses and Statutory Colleges Sources of Revenue/Survey of Fees, Volume 2, 1992 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 44)
    - Report on Physical Plant, 1979 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 45)
    - "The Research Foundation: A Distillation", Ca. 1971 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 46)
    - Research Foundation of SUNY, Annual Report, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 47)
    - Research Foundation, Decennial Report, 1951-1961 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 48)
    - Retirement Programs, 1968 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 49)
    - State University of New York Utilities, 1977 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 50)
    - "The Student in Higher Education" Report, The Hazen Foundation, 1968 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 51)
    - SUNY Administrative Resource System, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 53)
    - SUNY 2000: A Vision for the New Century, 1991 (Box 1 (4-Publications), Folder 52)
    - Task Force on SUNY Management Effectiveness, 1991 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Master Plans, SUNY, 1972; 1974; 1978; 4.3
    This sub-series was published by the State University of New York and includes drafts of plans to improve the SUNY system.
    - Master Plan of SUNY, 1972 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 2)
    - Progress Report on 1972 Master Plan, 1974 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 3)
    - Progress Report on 1976 Master Plan, 1978 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 4)
  - Newsletters and Programs, 1949-1999; 4.4
    Includes the Faculty Senate Bulletin, from volume 1 number 1 (1966) to volume 10 number 4 (June 1975) and, after a two-year hiatus, one issue of "the new Bulletin" (January 1978). The bulletin was published bi-monthly from October through June to promote the purposes and programs of the UFS, interpret and evaluate statewide University policy and provide a forum for the exchange of ideas among faculty of SUNY. Also included are a small group of broadsides put out by the Faculty Senate Bulletin; The News Quotes and The News of the Week.
    - Brochures, SUNY, 1949; 1954 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 5)
    - Brochures, SUNY, 1966-1974 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 6)
    - Faculty Senate Bulletin, 1966 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 7)
    - Faculty Senate Bulletin, 1967 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 8)
    - Faculty Senate Bulletin, 1968 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 9)
    - Faculty Senate Bulletin, 1969 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 10)
    - Faculty Senate Bulletin, 1970 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 11)
    - Faculty Senate Bulletin, 1971-1972 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 12)
    - Faculty Senate Bulletin, 1973 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 13)
    - Faculty Senate Bulletin, 1974 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 14)
    - Faculty Senate Bulletin, 1975 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 15)
    - Faculty Senate Bulletin, 1978 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 16)
    - Faculty Senate Bulletin, 1997-1998 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 17)
    - Faculty Senate Bulletin, 1998-1999 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 18)
    - "Futures: State University of New York and Your Children", Ca. 1962 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 19)
    - Guest Scholar Program, Program and Roster, 1981-1984 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 20)
    - Memo, Issue Number 5, 1969 February (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 21)
    - The News of The Week, Volume 1, Numbers 1-27, 1972 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 22)
    - The News of The Week, Volume 2, Numbers 2-24, 26, 1973 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 23)
    - The News of The Week, Volume 3, Numbers 1-12, 14, 1973-1974 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 24)
    - The News of The Week, Volume 4, Numbers 1-2, 4-6, 8-30, 1974-1975 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 25)
    - The News of The Week, Volume 5, Numbers 1-13, 1975 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 26)
    - The News Quotes, Volume 1, Numbers 1-2, 1972 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 27)
    - The News Reports, Volume 1, Numbers 1-2, Volume 2, Number 1, 1972-1973 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 28)
    - News Clippings, 1964-1978 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 29)
    - Sixty-four Campuses: The State University of New York to 1985 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 30)
    - Special Programs Commemoration, 1982 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 31)
    - Symposium on the Future, 1973 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 32)
    - Two Year Colleges, Profiles, 1979 (Box 2 (4-Publications), Folder 33)